<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
  <id>org.kde.okular.kirigami.desktop</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0+ and GFDL-1.3</project_license>
  <name>Okular Mobile</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca">Okular Mobile</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca-valencia">Okular Mobile</name>
  <name xml:lang="en-GB">Okular Mobile</name>
  <name xml:lang="es">Okular Mobile</name>
  <name xml:lang="gl">Okular Mobile</name>
  <name xml:lang="it">Okular Mobile</name>
  <name xml:lang="nl">Okular mobiel</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt">Okular Móvel</name>
  <name xml:lang="sk">Okular Mobile</name>
  <name xml:lang="sv">Okular Mobil</name>
  <name xml:lang="uk">Мобільний Okular</name>
  <name xml:lang="x-test">xxOkular Mobilexx</name>
  <summary>Document Viewer</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca">Visualitzador de documents</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca-valencia">Visualitzador de documents</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="en-GB">Document Viewer</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="es">Visor de documentos</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fr">Afficheur de document</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="gl">Visor de documentos</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="it">Visore di documenti</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nl">Documentenviewer</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt">Visualizador do Documento</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sk">Prehliadač dokumentov</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sv">Dokumentvisare</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="uk">Перегляд документів</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="x-test">xxDocument Viewerxx</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="zh-CN">文档查看器</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
   Okular is a universal document viewer developed by KDE. Okular works on multiple platforms, including but not limited to Linux, Windows, Mac OS X, *BSD, etc.
  </p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">L'Okular és un visualitzador universal de documents desenvolupat pel KDE. L'Okular funciona en diverses plataformes, incloent-hi però sense limitar en el Linux, Windows, Mac OS X, *BSD, etc.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">L'Okular és un visualitzador universal de documents desenvolupat pel KDE. L'Okular funciona en diverses plataformes, incloent-hi però sense limitar en el Linux, Windows, Mac OS X, *BSD, etc.</p>
    <p xml:lang="en-GB">Okular is a universal document viewer developed by KDE. Okular works on multiple platforms, including but not limited to Linux, Windows, Mac OS X, *BSD, etc.</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">Okular es un visor universal de documentos desarrollado por KDE. Okular funciona en diversas plataformas, incluidas Linux, Windows, Mac OS X, *BSD, etc.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">Okular est un afficheur universel de documents développé par KDE. Okular fonctionne sur de multiples plate-formes, comme Linux, Windows, Mac OS X, etc.</p>
    <p xml:lang="gl">Okular é un visor de documentos universal desenvolvido por KDE. Okular funciona en varias plataformas, entre elas Linux, Windows, Mac OS X, *BSD, etc.</p>
    <p xml:lang="it">Okular è un lettore universale di documenti sviluppato da KDE. Okular funziona su varie piattaforme, incluse (ma non solo) Linux, Windows, Mac OS X, *BSD, ecc.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Okular is een universele documentviewer ontwikkeld door KDE. Okular werkt op meerdere platforms, inclusief, maar niet beperkt tot Linux, Windows, Mac OS X, *BSD, etc.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">O Okular é um visualizador universal de documentos desenvolvido pelo KDE. O Okular funciona em diversas plataformas, incluindo mas não se limitando ao Linux, Windows, Mac OS X, *BSD, etc.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Okular är en universell dokumentvisare utvecklad av KDE. Okular fungerar på flera plattformar, inklusive men inte begränsat till Linux, Windows, Max OS X, *BSD, etc.</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Okular є універсальною програмою для перегляду документів, розробленою KDE. Okular може працювати на багатьох програмних платформах, зокрема Linux, Windows, Mac OS X, *BSD тощо.</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxOkular is a universal document viewer developed by KDE. Okular works on multiple platforms, including but not limited to Linux, Windows, Mac OS X, *BSD, etc.xx</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-CN">Okular 是由 KDE 开发的通用文档查看器。Okular 可在多个平台上运行，包括但不是限于 Linux，Windows，Mac OS X，* BSD，等。</p>
    <p>Features:</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">Característiques:</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Característiques:</p>
    <p xml:lang="en-GB">Features:</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">Funciones:</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">Fonctionnalités :</p>
    <p xml:lang="gl">Funcionalidades:</p>
    <p xml:lang="it">Funzionalità:</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Kenmerken:</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">Funcionalidades:</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">Funkcie:</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Funktioner:</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Можливості:</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxFeatures:xx</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-CN">功能：</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Supported Formats: PDF, PS, Tiff, CHM, DjVu, Images, DVI, XPS, ODT, Fiction Book, Comic Book, Plucker, EPub, Fax</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Formats acceptats: PDF, PS, Tiff, CHM, DjVu, imatges, DVI, XPS, ODT, Fiction Book, llibres de còmic, Plucker, EPub, Fax</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Formats acceptats: PDF, PS, Tiff, CHM, DjVu, imatges, DVI, XPS, ODT, Fiction Book, llibres de còmic, Plucker, EPub, Fax</li>
      <li xml:lang="en-GB">Supported Formats: PDF, PS, Tiff, CHM, DjVu, Images, DVI, XPS, ODT, Fiction Book, Comic Book, Plucker, EPub, Fax</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">Formatos permitidos: PDF, PS, Tiff, CHM, DjVu, imágenes, DVI, XPS, ODT, Fiction Book, libros de cómics, Plucker, EPub, Fax</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">Formats de fichiers gérés : PDF, PS, Tiff, CHM, DjVu, Images, DVI, XPS, ODT, Fiction Book, Comic Book, Plucker, EPub, Fax</li>
      <li xml:lang="gl">Formatos compatíbeis: PDF, PS, Tiff, CHM, DjVu, imaxes, DVI, XPS, ODT, FictionBook, banda deseñada, Plucker, EPub e fax.</li>
      <li xml:lang="it">Formati supportati: PDF, PS, Tiff, CHM, DjVu, immagini, DVI, XPS, ODT, Fiction Book, Comic Book, Plucker, EPub, Fax</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Ondersteunde formaten: PDF, PS, Tiff, CHM, DjVu, Afbeeldingen, DVI, XPS, ODT, Fictie boek, Stripboek, Plucker, EPub, Fax</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Formatos Suportados: PDF, PS, Tiff, CHM, DjVu, Imagens, DVI, XPS, ODT, Fiction Book, Comic Book, Plucker, EPub, Fax</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Format som stöds: PDF, PS, Tiff, CHM, DjVu, bilder, DVI, XPS, ODT, Fiction Book, Comic Book, Plucker, EPub, Fax</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Підтримувані формати: PDF, PS, Tiff, CHM, DjVu, зображення, DVI, XPS, ODT, Fiction Book, комікси, Plucker, EPub, факси.</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxSupported Formats: PDF, PS, Tiff, CHM, DjVu, Images, DVI, XPS, ODT, Fiction Book, Comic Book, Plucker, EPub, Faxxx</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-CN">支持的格式︰ PDF，PS，Tiff，CHM，DjVu，图片，DVI，XPS，ODT，FictionBook，漫画书，Plucker，EPub，传真</li>
      <li>Sidebar with contents, thumbnails, reviews and bookmarks</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Barra lateral amb el contingut, miniatures, revisions i punts</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Barra lateral amb el contingut, miniatures, revisions i punts</li>
      <li xml:lang="en-GB">Sidebar with contents, thumbnails, reviews and bookmarks</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">Barra lateral con contenido, miniaturas, revisiones y marcadores</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">Barre latérale montrant les contenus, miniatures, informations de relecture et signets</li>
      <li xml:lang="gl">Barra lateral con contido, miniaturas, revisións e marcadores.</li>
      <li xml:lang="it">Barra laterale con contenuti, miniature, revisioni e segnalibri</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Zijbalk met inhoud, miniaturen, reviews en bladwijzers</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Barra lateral com o conteúdo, miniaturas, revisões e marcação de favoritos</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Sidorad med innehåll, miniatyrbilder, granskningar och bokmärken</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Бічні панелі зі списками змісту, мініатюрами сторінок, можливість рецензування та додавання закладок.</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxSidebar with contents, thumbnails, reviews and bookmarksxx</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-CN">目录，缩略图，批注和书签侧边栏</li>
      <li>Annotations support</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Admet anotacions</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Admet anotacions</li>
      <li xml:lang="en-GB">Annotations support</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">Permite el uso de notas</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">Gestion des annotations</li>
      <li xml:lang="gl">Funcionalidade de anotacións.</li>
      <li xml:lang="it">Supporto per annotazioni</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Ondersteuning van annotaties</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Suporte para anotações</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Stöd för kommentarer</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Підтримка анотування.</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxAnnotations supportxx</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-CN">支持批注</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://www.kde.org/images/screenshots/okular.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <url type="homepage">https://okular.kde.org/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://bugs.kde.org/enter_bug.cgi?format=guided&amp;product=okular</url>
  <project_group>KDE</project_group>
  <provides>
    <binary>okularkirigami</binary>
  </provides>
</component>
